<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.subsoundorg.Subsound</id>

  <name>Subsound</name>
  <summary>Stream music from your Navidrome Server</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>
      Subsound is a GTK4/Adwaita music player for Subsonic-compatible streaming servers,
      with Navidrome as the primary target. It lets you browse artists, albums, and playlists
      from your personal music server and plays them back directly or from a local cache.
    </p>
    <p>Features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Browse and play music from Navidrome or any Subsonic-compatible server</li>
      <li>Playlist management</li>
      <li>Starred songs and downloaded songs views</li>
      <li>Offline playback from a local song cache</li>
      <li>Offline first scrobble back to server</li>
      <li>MPRIS media player integration for desktop media controls</li>
      <li>Native GTK4/Adwaita interface designed for GNOME</li>
    </ul>
    <p>For offline mode, remember to first Sync Library.</p>
  </description>

  <developer id="io.github.subsoundorg">
    <name>Eivind Larsen</name>
  </developer>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.subsoundorg.Subsound.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/subsoundorg/Subsound</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/subsoundorg/Subsound/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/subsoundorg/Subsound</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The Artist overview tab</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/subsoundorg/Subsound/main/screenshots/artistsv3.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/subsoundorg/Subsound/main/screenshots/starredv8.png</image>
      <caption>The Playlist view</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/subsoundorg/Subsound/main/screenshots/searchv3.png</image>
      <caption>The Quick Search box (Ctrl+K)</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#63452c</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#241f31</color>
  </branding>

  <releases>
    <release version="@version@" date="2026-05-18">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>New: desktop media controls can now toggle shuffle and repeat via MPRIS, and reflect the current mode</li>
          <li>New: activating Subsound from desktop media controls now raises the window to the foreground</li>
          <li>Bugfix: improved track meta sent over MPRIS</li>
          <li>Bugfix: sometimes the currently playing row was not highlighted correctly after shuffle</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.1" date="2026-05-06">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>New: Settings page now shows which OpenSubsonic extensions your server supports</li>
          <li>Improved: app startup is faster when the server is unreachable or you are offline</li>
          <li>Improved: opening the Downloads playlist is now much faster for large libraries</li>
          <li>Improved: album action menu is properly sized</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-05-02">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>New: redesigned playback scrubber with a cleaner look and feel</li>
          <li>New: sort playlists by title or artist by clicking the column header</li>
          <li>New: reportPlayback: playback progress is reported to your server in real time on servers that advertise OpenSubsonic playback reporting</li>
          <li>Improved: more server details shown on the Settings page</li>
          <li>Improved: artist, album-artist and mood metadata are now stored locally for richer offline browsing</li>
          <li>Improved: faster playlist scrolling and album-art rendering, especially for large libraries</li>
          <li>Bugfix: re-downloading a song now always fetches the current transcoded format from the server</li>
          <li>Bugfix: shuffle and repeat buttons in the player bar now show the correct state right after startup</li>
          <li>Bugfix: fixed a race where the same song could start downloading twice at once</li>
          <li>Bugfix: fixed sizing of the onboarding/server-config form so it no longer renders too narrow</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.20" date="2026-04-19">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>New: "Now Playing" is reported to your server while you listen, so other Subsonic clients can see what's playing</li>
          <li>New: seek support over MPRIS — jump to any position in the current track from desktop media controls</li>
          <li>Bugfix: Fixed scrobble occasionally being recorded against the next track in the queue instead of the one that just finished</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.19" date="2026-04-18">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>New: quick-filter search in playlist views — press Ctrl+F or start typing to filter by title, artist, or album</li>
          <li>New: download status counter so you can see at a glance how many songs are downloaded</li>
          <li>New: offline play history is now kept and scrobbled back to the server when you come back online</li>
          <li>"Clear song cache" now immediately updates the song list and download counts</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where cover art could fail to load under spotty network conditions</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.17" date="2026-04-17">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Play queue is now saved and restored across app restarts</li>
          <li>Fixed sometimes app not exiting cleanly</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.6.16" date="2026-04-15">
      <description>
        <p>Fixed issue deleting from playlists</p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.6.15" date="2026-04-12">
      <description>
        <p>Initial public release.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Browse albums</li>
          <li>Browse artists</li>
          <li>Browse playlists</li>
          <li>Offline mode</li>
          <li>MPRIS Support</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.0" date="2026-03-07">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
